<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on San Antonio Tech Dads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on San Antonio Tech Dads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 13:49:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned in Opens Source Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2015/08/18/lessons-learned-in-opens-source-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 13:49:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2015/08/18/lessons-learned-in-opens-source-development/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re curious how a Windows developer would go about starting an open source project, you aren&amp;rsquo;t alone. In fact, our most recent Office Hours Hangout guest, Don Schecnk, found himself ready to start an open source project, and didn&amp;rsquo;t know where to start. Fortunately for us, he documented his process, and spoke with us about it on our hangout. We didn&amp;rsquo;t just cover the process, we also covered the product of his efforts, PoshStack, the PowerShell client for OpenStack. I&amp;rsquo;m including a few selected highlights, but the entire video can be viewed below. This was a fun interview - I know I learned a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;container&#34;&gt;
&lt;audio controls&gt;
        &lt;source src=&#34;http://drops.albush.com/Windows%20Development%20with%20Rackspace%20Developer%20Don%20Schenck.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mp4&#34;&gt;
        &lt;source src=&#34;http://drops.albush.com/Windows%20Development%20with%20Rackspace%20Developer%20Don%20Schenck.ogg&#34; type=&#34;audio/ogg&#34;&gt;
        Sorry, your browser does not support the &lt;code&gt;audio&lt;/code&gt; element.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://drops.albush.com/Windows%20Development%20with%20Rackspace%20Developer%20Don%20Schenck.mp3&#34;&gt;MP3&lt;/a&gt; (37 MB) | &lt;a href=&#34;http://drops.albush.com/Windows%20Development%20with%20Rackspace%20Developer%20Don%20Schenck.ogg&#34;&gt;OGG&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Subscribe: Coming Soon.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-container&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/u7dlGhhQ48k&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;poshstack:f8f7ec867f77ab40852c5bdf31ec7080&#34;&gt;PoshStack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started our conversation by speaking about PowerShell: what it is, why developers and administrators use it. Don related the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u7dlGhhQ48k?t=3m29s&#34;&gt;story of PoshStack came to be&lt;/a&gt;. Don also shared a story of being able to &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u7dlGhhQ48k?t=9m9s&#34;&gt;spin up dozens of servers&lt;/a&gt; for a training event. PoshStack made it possible to automate that deployment (and subsequent spin down). Another task for PoshStack is to work in conjunction with a configuration management solution, such as Ansible. Don himself worked with the creators of Ansible to build the Windows version of Ansible, and enjoys the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u7dlGhhQ48k?t=15m23s&#34;&gt;consistent environment&lt;/a&gt; he&amp;rsquo;s able to reproduce with these tools. I really appreciated how this bit of the conversation was an extension of our Hangout last week, with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rackspace.com/blog/ansible-certified-engineer-justin-phelps-video/&#34;&gt;Ansible Certified Engineer Justin Phelps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-experience-of-building-an-open-source-project:f8f7ec867f77ab40852c5bdf31ec7080&#34;&gt;The experience of building an open source project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PoshStack is a great tool for anyone working extensively on Windows severs. It&amp;rsquo;s also a great case study in building an open source project. Don is new to open source, so he decided to document his &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u7dlGhhQ48k?t=19m15s&#34;&gt;experiences building an open source project?&lt;/a&gt;, eventually turning his experience into a presentation given at various conferences. During our conversation, Don outlined several &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u7dlGhhQ48k?t=21m20s&#34;&gt;lessons learned&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u7dlGhhQ48k?t=29m11s&#34;&gt;tools used&lt;/a&gt;, and things he would have &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u7dlGhhQ48k?t=36m16s&#34;&gt;done differently&lt;/a&gt;. I enjoyed chatting with Don on these points; they&amp;rsquo;re great advice for anyone interested in getting started in open source, and probably even a few with plenty of experience. Among the things to try differently, I found his advice around slowing down to be especially helpful. Don recommended paying extra attention to the README file. That introduction to your project should give potential users and contributers a solid foundation to start with. Don recommended that &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u7dlGhhQ48k?t=38m1s&#34;&gt;each README contain four characteristics&lt;/a&gt;: A description, a list of prerequisites, complete installation instructions, and notes on how to contribute. Most importantly, Don encourages anyone interested in working on a project to &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u7dlGhhQ48k?t=42m50s&#34;&gt;just get out there and start contributing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rack-cli:f8f7ec867f77ab40852c5bdf31ec7080&#34;&gt;rack cli&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wrapped up our conversation with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u7dlGhhQ48k?t=43m38s&#34;&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt; on the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.rackspace.com/blog/introducing-rack-global-cli/&#34;&gt;rack command line interface&lt;/a&gt; for Windows, Mac OS X, and Linux. Rack cli is very easy to install and configure - I was able to get up and running in about 5 minutes. The interface allows the user to command Cloud Servers, Cloud Files, Cloud Block Storage, and Cloud Networks. Rack cli even &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u7dlGhhQ48k?t=45m13s&#34;&gt;integrates well with PoshStack&lt;/a&gt;; users can send rack cli output directly into PoshStack for further work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I truly enjoyed chatting with Don. &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u7dlGhhQ48k?t=53m28s&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s obvious that he loves his job&lt;/a&gt;, and that love shows in the amazing tools he&amp;rsquo;s built. You can view the entire discussion below, and don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out our next hangout, Thursday at 1pm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>